SHEHZAD NOOR TAUS PRIYO

STUDENT. RESEARCHER & SOFTWARE ENGINEER

sntaus@gmail.com +1 (778) 681-3331

PHP 5.3

www.taus.xyz

linkedin.com/in/sntaus

Micros
CERTIF
Professio
Develop



ABOUT ME

Programming took over my life at an early age of ten. Since then, I have been writing code and experimenting with various startup ideas. My areas of expertise include full stack web application development on multiple platforms (PHP, NodeJS, Ruby on Rails, AngularJS, KnockoutJS) and smartphone application development using Cordova. Currently, I am pursuing a BSc on Computer Science at UBC, hoping to graduate in 2019, and working at Picatic as a full stack developer. Other than that, I am also studying machine learning on my own to build intelligent applications.



WORK EXPERIENCE

PICATIC

Full Stack Developer, May 2016 - present

Working primarily on the development (both front and back end) of Picatic, an online ticketing app. Technologies used include PHP, JS (both client and server side) and Golang.

THE UNIVERSITY OF BRITISH COLUMBIA

Computer Science Researcher, Nov 2015 - Apr 2016

Texada, an open source data mining tool built for researchers
Using AngularJS for the front end (writing tests on Protractor
(e2e) and Jasmine), Go lang for the web server and C++ for the

ThirdEye, Facebook Insider Attack Identification
Using machine learning algorithms from scikit learn (Python) to
mine data on and distinguish between normal Facebook usage
and insider attacks.

MICROSOFT

Developer Intern, Jun 2015 - Jul 2015

Worked on a Windows application that communicated with the Microsoft Azure cloud, built using C# on Visual Studio, and helped promote Microsoft's development and cloud technologies.

INCOGMITO

Co-founder, Apr 2014 - Apr 2015

Incogmito, an anonymous social networking application
Used PHP and MySQL for the backend and KnockoutJS with
Bootstrap on Cordova for the mobile app.

MBSOFTWARE

Software Developer Intern, Jun 2011 - Jul 2011

Okdo.it, an email-based task management system
Worked with the Zend PHP Framework alongside SQLite and
MySQL on the backend and integrated Facebook, Twitter &
LinkedIn login and sync features



EDUCATION

THE UNIVERSITY OF BRITISH COLUMBIA

Vancouver, Canada, 2015-2019 BSc - Computer Science



AWARDS

INTERNATIONAL LEADER OF TOMORROW (ILOT)

Vancouver, Canada, 2015

ILOT is a full ride scholarship, worth around \$200,000, awarded by The University of British Columbia to around 25 students each year.

DEAN'S HONOUR LIST

Vancouver, Canada, 2016

Dean's Honour List is an academic distinction awarded by UBC to students across different faculties to recognize their strong performance and commitment to academics.



PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

JavaScript	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•
Golang	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•
PHP	•	•	•	•	•	()	•	•	•
Python	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	0
Java	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	0
C/C++	•	•	•	•	•	O	•	•	0
Ruby	•	•	•	•	•	O	O	0	0
C#	•	•	•	•	•	•	0	0	0



PLATFORMS AND FRAMEWORKS

AngularJS	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•
SailsJS (Node.js)	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•
jQuery		•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•
api2go		•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•
Twitter Bootstrap		•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•
Laravel		•	•	•	•	•	•	•	0
Rails		•	•	•	•	•	•	•	0
scikit Learn		•	•	•	•	•	•	0	0



OTHER PROJECTS

EDURETO

2012-2013

EduReto was a social Learning Management System (LMS) built using a custom MVC framework on PHP and Bootstrap with jQuery.

XPRESSERS

2010-2012

Xpressers was a social networking application built on PHP. It featured a fully AJAX-based user interface avoiding full-page reload and different features like a WYSIWYG profile with embedded widgets (using embed.ly).